안녕, 뭐 하고 있어?
-What you guys doing?
-Monica's making us watch Old Yeller.
모니카가 '늙은 누렁이'를
보자고 해서
Why are you guys upset?
It's Old Yeller. It's a happy movie.
그런데 다들 왜 그래?
재미있는 영화잖아
-What?
-What are you talking about?
- 뭐?
- 뭐라고?
단란한 가정에 개가 생기고
웃긴 일만 터지잖아
Come on. Happy family gets a dog.
Frontier fun!
그래도 끝은 슬퍼
Pheebs, what about the end?
누렁이가 늑대로부터 가족을
구하고 모두 행복해지는데?
When Yeller saves the family
and everyone's happy?
- 그게 끝이 아냐
- 끝이야
That's not the end.
That's when my mother would
shut off the TV and say, "The end."
우리 엄마가 TV를 끄면서
'끝! '이라고 하셨어
그럼 개가 광견병에 걸리는
부분은?
What about when he has rabies?
He doesn't have rabies.
He has babies.
광견병이 아니라
새끼를 밴 거야
That's what my mom said.
우리 엄마가 그러셨어
끝이 어떻게 되는지
보이고 싶지 않으셨던 거야
I don't think she'd want you
to see what's about to happen.
끝이 어떻게 되는데요?
Why? What's about to happen?
I've never seen this part.
저런 장면도 있었나?
Hey, Travis, what you doing
with that gun?
트레비스, 총을 어디다 쏘려고?
안 돼, 총 내려놔
Oh, no.
No, no, Travis, put down the gun.
안 돼, 걔는 네 친구 누렁이라고
No, no, he's your buddy.
He's your Yeller.
No! The end! The end!
영화 끝내, 끝!
Okay, what kind of a sick
doggy snuff film is this?
이런 개 같은 영화가 어딨어!
The One Where Old Yeller Dies
Have you guys eaten? Richard and l
just finished, and we've got leftovers.
너희들 밥 먹었니?
리차드와 내가 먹던 게 남았거든
Chicken and potatoes.
통닭하고 감자야
What am I wearing?
내가 뭘 입고 있냐구?
고무장갑만 꼈다 왜?
Actually, nothing but rubber gloves.
One of these times, you'll really
be naked and we won't come over.
진짜 다 벗고 있었으면
안 들어왔어
봐준다
다리랑 가슴, 날개가 남았어
I got a leg, three breasts
and a wing.
언제 그렇게 옷을 입었니?
How do you find clothes that fit?
Hey, Monica? We got a question.
모니카, 물어 볼 게 있어
All right, yes, I see other women
in the shower at the gym.
수도 없이 말하지만
체육관에서 샤워할 때
다른 여자들 쳐다본 적 없어
And no, I don't look.
그거 말고 닉스 경기표가
한 장 남았는데 누구랑 갈까?
No, not that one.
We're figuring out who to bring
to the Nicks game.
Ross can't go, so it's between my friend
Eric Prower, who has breath issues...
로스가 못 간다니까
입 냄새 죽이는 에릭하고
...and Dan, with the poking.
"Did you see that play?"
찌르기 선수 댄 중에
고르게 생겼어
"You want more beer?
Is that Spike Lee?"
'저번 경기 봤냐? 콜라 마실래?
쟤가 스파이크 리냐?'
그만 해
Why don't you ask Richard?
리차드한테 말해 봐
Richard, if you had an extra
ticket to the Nicks game...
리차드, 만약 당신한테
닉스 경기표가 남는다면
...and you had to choose between
a friend who smelled...
냄새나는 친구와 찌르기 선수
중에 누구하고 갈래요?
...and one who bruises you,
who would you pick?
닉스 팬 입장에서 말하자면
닉스 팬과 가는 게 좋겠어
Being a huge Nicks fan myself...
... I think you should take someone
who's a huge Nicks fan.
알았어요
That's Eric.
그럼 에릭이네
도움이 됐다니 기쁘군
Glad to be of help.
Matches.
I meant, why don't you
take Richard to the game?
내 말은 리차드와 함께
가면 어떠냐는 거였어
What?
왜?
-I don't know.
-Come on!
글쎄...
리차드는 뭐든 직접 하고
생각하는 것도 신선하다고
He keeps his fingers to himself,
and he's always minty fresh.
Richard's really nice.
We just don't know him really well.
그렇게 멋진 사람이
우리와 어울리겠어?
게다가 나이가 너무 많아
Plus, he's old
er than some people.
어떤 사람들보다는 많다는 거지
But younger than some buildings.
어떤 건물에 비하면
아주 젊기도 하고
So what, he's a little older.
Big deal.
나이가 들긴 했지만
그래도 내겐 소중한 사람이야
He's important to me.
가자고 하면
재규어를 태워 줄지도 몰라
If you ask him,
he might take you in his Jag.
How do we say yes...
차를 타고 싶어서라는 낌새를
풍기지 않고 허락해야겠지?
...and make it seem like it's not
just to ride in the cool car?
- 그래, 신중해야 돼
- 좋아
Okay, this could be tough.
모니카, 함께 갈게
재규어를 몰고 간다면 말야
We'll bring him,
but only if he takes the Jaguar.
You almost had it.
거의 감쪽같았어
No, no, you're fine. You're fine.
아냐, 안 쌌어
- 우리 왔어
- 왔어?
안녕, 우리 아기
Hi, honey.
- 무슨 일이 있었는지 알아?
- 뭔데
You are not gonna believe
what happened!
We were playing on the floor,
and he grabs the table...
마루에서 놀다가 혼자
탁자를 잡고 벌떡 일어섰어
...and he pulls himself up!
He pulled himself up!
혼자 섰다고
Standing man!
사나이라니까
I'm sorry you missed it,
but I did tape it if you wanna see it.
그걸 놓치다니 안됐다
녹화해 놨으니까 보고 싶음 봐
벌써 봤어
지난주에도 섰는걸
We know. He already did it last week.
녹화해 놓은 거 볼래요?
You can watch our tape if you want.
See, I don't believe this.
I missed the first time of everything.
너무해
난 매일 첫 장면을 놓쳐
The first time he rolled over,
the first time he crawled.
구르기, 기어가기
다 못 봤어
What else? Has he spoken?
Is he driving?
이러다간 첫 말, 첫 운전
처음 술 마시는 것도 놓칠 거야
Does he have a favorite liqueur?
이제는 말을 할 단계야
He is getting closer
on the talking thing.
He can't quite say "mama" yet,
but once he said "Yemen."
얼마 전엔 '엄마' 대신
'어마'라고 하지 뭐야
See, I don't know.
I'm so sick of missing stuff.
전부 놓치니까 짜증이 나
I want him for more than a day.
I want him for a whole weekend.
일주일 내내 같이 있을 수
있다면 놓치지 않을 텐데
Listen. I feel
좋아, 그렇게 해
That would be great.
진심이야?
말 연습을 얼마나 시켰는데
Really? I had a whole speech prepared.
Oh, shoot, that would've been fun.
정말 재미있었겠네요
방금 봤어?
벤이 손을 흔들었어
Did you just see that?
Did you see? He just waved!
He just waved!
이거야말로 처음일 거야
정말이야!
He's never waved before!
Yes, he has. Very good.
잘했다, 벤
피비, 그게 뭐니?
What you got there?
Love Story, Brian's Song and
Terms of Endearment.
'러브스토리', '브라이언의 노래'
'애정의 조건'이야
All you need now is The Killing Fields
and guacamole, and you got a party!
'킬링필드'랑 먹을 것만 있으면
혼자서 파티해도 되겠다
할머니한테 '늙은 누렁이'
얘기를 했더니 할머니 말씀이
I talked to my grandma
about the Old Yeller incident...
...and she said my mom used to not
show us the ends of sad movies...
엄마가 일부러 슬픈 영화의
끝 장면을 못 보게 하셨대
고통과 슬픔으로부터
보호해 주신 거지
...to shield us from
the pain and sadness.
You know, before she killed herself.
자살하시기 전까지 말야
- 안녕?
리차드는 어디 있어?
따돌린 거 아냐?
Where's Richard?
Did you ditch him?
After we stole his lunch money
and gave him a wedgie.
점심 값을 훔쳐서 튀었다
What's the matter?
He's parking the car.
정말 그랬겠냐?
지금 주차하고 있어
-Did you guys have fun?
-Your boyfriend is so cool.
- 재미있었어?
- 네 남자친구 멋지더라
- 정말?
- 재규어도 몰게 해줬어
He let us drive his Jaguar.
Joey for 12 blocks. Me for 15.
조이가 12블록을 몰고
내가 15블록을 몰았어
너희를 믿었나 보다
He must like you best.
What about when he tipped the guy
who showed us to our seats?
우리 자리를 찾아 준 사람한테
팁 주는 거 봤지?
You never even saw the money.
돈을 건네는지도 몰랐어
- 챈들러, 자리 찾아 줘서 고맙네
- 뭘요
Hey, Chandler, thanks for
showing us to our seats.
You're welcome. Hey, Joey,
thanks for parking the car.
- 조이, 주차해 줘서 고맙네
- 별거 아닌데요
No problem.
-Hey, Chandler
-I think they get it.
- 챈들러?
- 다 알아들었어
주인공이 오시는군
There's the man!
Hey, you're getting better.
이제 잘하네
- 내 팁으로 넣어 두지
- 그래요
I'm gonna keep this.
He kept my dollar.
진짜로 가져갔어
Your first weekend without Ben.
What are you doing?
벤 없이 일주일 간
뭘 할 거죠?
민속촌이 있는
윌리엄스 버그에 갈 거야
We're going to
colonial Williamsburg.
A woman I went to college with is
the first female blacksmith there.
대학동창이 거기서
첫 여자 대장장이로 있어요
They're a little behind the times
in colonial Williamsburg.
윌리엄스 버그는 약간
시대에 뒤쳐진 곳이지
Look, I better go
before Mommy starts weeping.
눈물 나오기 전에
어서 가야겠다
- 안녕
- 사랑한다
-We love you.
-Bye, Mommy.
- 안녕
- 잘지내
Have a good time.
- 오빠?
- 왜?
Look.
저것 봐
Joey, do you know
we can see you from here?
조이, 우리가 보고 있는 거 알아?
How come Richard looks cooler
with one of these?
리차드가 물면 멋지던데
왜 난 안 어울리지?
넌 초보니까 그렇지
불붙이고 아래턱을 빼 봐
You may wanna light it
and lose the spatula.
리차드 흉내내니까
너무 귀엽다
It's cute, you trying
to be more like Richard.
Not like him, per se.
흉내내는 거 아냐
그를 안 닮지 않았을 뿐이지
Just not unlike him.
이전에 챈들러라고 불리웠던
예술가시구만
It's the artist formerly known
as Chandler.
수염을 좀 길러 보려고
I'm just trying something here,
you know?
조이, 수염도 기르지 그랬어?
Why didn't you grow a mustache?
내가 시가를 피우고
챈들러가 수염을 기르기로 했어
We flipped for it.
I got the cigar,
he got the mustache.
둘 다 수염을 길렀으면
얼뜨기 같았을 거야
If we both grew them,
we'd look like dorks.
내가 하고 싶었던 말을
잘 해줬어
You really sidestepped
that land mine.
참, 빨리 가야지
리차드와 만나기로 했잖아
I promised Richard
we'd meet him downstairs.
- 리차드를 만나?
- 전쟁놀이를 하기로 했어
You're meeting Richard?
-Ranger game.
-Didn't he tell you?
얘기 못 들었어?
He said he was going out with the guys.
I didn't know that was you.
친구들하고 나간다곤 했지만
너희가 그 '친구들'인진 몰랐어
You hear that?
- 들었어? 우리더러 친구랬대
- 우린 친구야
We're the guys!
With that mustache,
he reminds me of Aunt Sylvia.
챈들러 꼭 수염 기른
여자 같지?
그거야!
Thank you!
견학 나왔어요
Hi. We're visiting.
It's Ben and his dada.
벤과 그의 빠빠예요
빠빠
Can you say "dada"?
'빠빠' 할 수 있지?
I'm telling your mommies you said it,
so you might as well.
네 엄마들한테 자랑해야 하니까
너도 노력해
No luck, huh?
- 잘될까?
- 좀전에 '두'라고 말했어
A while ago,
I got a "seh" out of him...
'두 번째로 신경 써 주는 사람'
이라고 말하고 싶었을 거야
...which I thought might turn into
"seh-condary caregiver," but....
Would you hold him for a sec?
I gotta take this off.
잠깐만 들고 있을래?
가방 좀 내릴게
Sure. Okay.
- 뭐 하는 거야?
- 들고 있으라며
What are you doing?
I'm holding Ben.
벤은 폭탄이 아냐
He's a baby, not a bomb.
나도 알아
축구공을 들 듯이 들어
Hold him like you'd hold a football.
난 축구공 이렇게 들어
This is how I would hold a football.
Here. Here. There we go.
- 알았어, 됐어
- 미안해, 어색해서 그래
Sorry, I'm not very good with babies.
I haven't been around them.
주위에 아기가 있었던 적이
없었어, 어렸을 때 빼고
I mean, you know, since I was one.
-It's all right. No big deal.
-Really?
- 괜찮아, 별일도 아닌데
- 정말?
그럼, 우리 아기가 생기면
달라질 거야
I'm sure you'll feel different
when it's our baby.
-What?
- 뭐?
- 뭐라니?
You think about stuff like that?
그런 걸 생각하고 있었어?
그럼
Yeah. I mean....
내 생각에는...
Actually, I kind of think
that we'll have two babies.
둘은 낳아야겠지?
둘씩이나?
Two babies?
딸 하나, 아들 하나
You know, a boy and a girl.
딸이 먼저 나오면
벤이 경쟁심을 안 느낄 거야
Hopefully, the girl will come first,
so Ben won't feel competitive.
Then what's gonna happen?
그런 다음에는?
We won't wanna raise kids in the city,
so we'll move to Scarsdale.
도시에서 키울 순 없으니까
스카스데일로 가는 거야
거기면 부모님과 멀리
떨어져 있는 것도 아니니까
We'll be far enough from our parents
so we don't have to see them...
필요하다면 아이들을
봐 달라고 할 수도 있지
... but close enough
that they can baby-sit.
물론 거기가 세금은 좀
비싸긴 하지만
And yes, I know the taxes are
a little higher than Nassau County...
... but the school system's great.
교육제도가 잘 돼 있거든
Wow, that's great! Great!
대단해, 정말
저 말이야...
Okay, wow! You know what?
이제 일을 해야 되니까
I'm off my break now.
이건 자기가 들어
Here. You take this.
난 손님들한테 커피 좀
부어 줘야겠어
I'm gonna go pour these
very nice people some coffee.
이런, 커피포트를
안 가져왔네
Look at that. I don't have a pot.
I don't have a pot.
Maybe I've got one at home.
집에 하나 있을 거야
아님 스카스데일에 있거나
Or in Scarsdale.
Hey, is that a door?
저게 문이지?
레이첼!
- 안녕하세요?
- 피비, 무슨 일이야?
Hey, Pheebs. What's happening?
살인, 암, 축구팀이 안데스
산맥에서 서로를 먹질 않나...
Murder, cancer, soccer teams eating
each other in the Andes.
So you watched the movies?
그 비디오들 봤구나?
What is happening to the world?
세상이 어떻게 돌아가는 거야?
I mean....
No, no, because E.T. Ieaves...
ET도 떠나고 록키는 자고
샤를롯은 죽고
...and Rocky loses. Charlotte dies.
Charlotte who?
샤를롯이라니?
With the web. The spider.
'스파이더'에서 죽잖아요
아기를 낳다가요
She dies. She has babies and dies.
It's like, "Welcome home
from the hospital." Thud!
병원에서 돌아오자마자, 쿵!
- 재미있는 거 줄까?
응
You wanna feel better?
Here. Watch this.
여기 있어, 이걸 봐
'멋진 인생'?
들어 본 적 있어
It's a Wonderful Life.
I've heard of this.
실망하지 않을 거야
제목처럼 멋진 일들만 일어나
So you can't lose.
It's there in the title.
Wonderfulness is baked right in.
'양키의 자존심'에 완전히
속은 적이 있어
I fell for that with
Pride of the Yankees.
I thought I'd see a film
about Yankee pride.
난 양키의 자존심에 관한
영화인 줄 알았는데
And boom! The guy gets
Lou Gehrig's disease.
루게릭 병 환자 얘기더라
The guy was Lou Gehrig.
Didn't you kind of see it coming?
주인공 이름이 루게릭이야
그거 끝까지 안 봤지?
피비, 그거 보고 나면
인간애를 다시 되찾을 거야
Watch that. It'll restore
all your faith in humanity.
Hey, big guy. Game time.
- 친구, 게임해야죠
- 먼저 가 있어
-Hey! Be right there!
-There's a game?
- 게임요?
- 스틱을 하나 더 구했지
I just got my Pik-Up Stiks
back from the shop.
각오 단단히 해요
Bring your nerves of steel.
It's the basketball playoffs.
축구 경기야
I appreciate this, but you don't
have to hang out with them for me.
자기, 나 때문에 쟤들한테
너무 잘해 줄 필요 없어요
- 저 둘이서도 잘 놀아요
- 아냐, 걱정하지 마
They have each other.
Oh, no, honey. I mean, don't worry.
저 친구들하고 노는 게 좋아
내 친구들하곤 다르거든
I like hanging out with them.
They're different than my other friends.
눈 치우다가 누가 죽었다는
얘기도 안 하고 말야
They don't start sentences with
"You know who just died shoveling snow?"
좋아요, 가세요
All right, that's great.
Then just go.
Go Nicks!
- 잘해요, 닉스!
- 거긴 아마추어 수준이야
It's the college playoffs.
- 그럼 잘해요, 바자르!
- 그런 축구팀은 없어
-Then, go Vassar!
-They're not in it.
Okay, then just go.
- 그럼 그냥 가 버려요
- 알았어
Why does this bother me so much?
왜 기분이 이렇지?
I'm not one of those people who wants
to spend 24 hours a day together.
애인이 스포츠 얘기만 한다고
불평하는 여자는 되기 싫은데
당연하지
Sure.
자유시간이 많으면 또 몰라
난 어쩌라고?
He just doesn't have much free time.
What do I do?
어쩌긴? 죽든지 갈라서든지
애완동물을 발로 차 버려!
Does it matter? You'll just die
or divorce or blow your pet's head off.
나도 미치겠어!
Me too!
레이첼, 얘기 좀 해
리차드가 또 놀러 나갔어
Rachel, I got a question. Richard
made plans again with the guys
로스는 백년계획을 세웠어
Ross made plans for the century.
I'm gonna go read Cosmo.
Maybe there's something helpful in it.
너희들한테 얘기하느니
잡지를 읽는 게 낫겠다
If not, I can learn how to do a bikini
wax with leftover Christmas candles.
최소한 성탄절 초로 수영복
왁스칠하는 법은 배우겠지
좋아, 대체 왜 이러는 거야?
What happened back there?
I don't know. You tell me.
내가 알아? 난 그저 벤을
축구공처럼 든 것뿐인데
One minute I'm holding Ben,
then I've got two kids...
아이를 둘 낳고 스카스데이로
이사가서 세금 걱정을 하라며?
... I'm living in Scarsdale
complaining about taxes!
Well, I'm sorry.
I think about stuff.
미안해, 그건 내 생각일 뿐이야
넌 일하고 돈을 모아서
정신수양이나 해야지
You're at work, you're assembling bones,
your mind wanders.
You've planned out the next 20 years.
We've dated for six weeks!
사귄 지 6주밖에 안 됐는데
20년 후의 계획을 세워?
그럼 넌 우리 미래 생각 안 해?
You never think about our future?
'내일은 누구 집에서 잘까 아님
토요일에 어디서 외식할까'지
I think about whose apartment
we'll sleep at tomorrow...
...and where we'll have dinner
next Saturday!
낳지도 않은 애 이름 때문에
고민하진 않아!
I do not think about
our children's names!
You know what our
children's names will be?
벌써 지은 건 아닐 테지?
아냐
No, I mean, you know. I read a book,
and there was a girl named Emily.
책 읽다가 에밀리란 이름을 보고
그게 괜찮다고 생각했을 뿐이야
And I thought that might be good.
What book?
책 제목이 뭔데?
'아이 이름 대사전'
The Big Book of Children's Names.
로스, 들어 봐
Okay, listen.
What we have is amazing.
- 물론 우리 사이는 좋아
- 그래!
But I do not want
everything decided for me!
그렇다고 내 계획까지
자기가 세울 수는 없어
지금까지 모두 그런 식이었어
I spent my whole life like that.
베리랑도 그래서 헤어진 거라구
난 지금 이 상태가 좋아
It's what I had with Barry.
That's a reason I left.
I like not knowing right now.
Sorry if that scares you, but if you
wanna be with me, deal with that!
미안하지만 나랑 사귀려면
미리 상의를 해줘!
- 알았어, 좋아
- 고마워
-Okay, fine!
-Thank you!
- 아직 안 끝났어
- 진작 말하지
-We're not done!
-I didn't know that.
너랑 미래를 계획하지 않고는
못 견디는 남자니까 이해해 줘
You're with a guy who won't stop
planning his future with you.
He knows we'll end up together.
결국 우린 결혼할 테니까
그게 겁나더라도 견뎌!
If that scares you, tough!
You'll have to deal with that.
- 좋아, 그러지 뭐
- 널 사랑하니까 이러는 거야
-I will!
-Good, because I love you!
- 그래?
- 응
Oh, yeah? I love you too!
- 나도 자길 사랑해
- 사랑한단 말은 처음이야
-That's the first time we've said that!
-Yes, it is!
- 맞아
- 너한테 키스할 거야
-I'm gonna kiss you!
-You better!
그러는 게 좋겠어
- 안녕?
- 피비
Thanks for the great movie tip.
- 좋은 영화 고마워
- 마음에 들어?
-Did you like it?
-Oh, yeah.
응, 그런데 언제
기뻐해야 할지 모르겠더라
I don't know if I was happier when
George Bailey destroyed the business...
조지가 사업에 망했을 땐지
도나가 울었을 땐지
...or Donna Reed cried or when
the pharmacist made his ear bleed.
약사가 자기 귀를
찢었을 때였는지 말야
I'll give you the ear thing,
but wasn't the ending wonderful?
그래도 끝은 멋있지?
I didn't watch it.
I was too depressed.
실망해서 끝은 안 봤어
볼수록 추악해져
It kept getting worse!
It should've been called:
이런 제목이 더 어울리겠다
"It's a Sucky Life, And Just When You
Think It Can't Suck Anymore, It Does!"
'거지같은 인생
이보다 더할 순 없다'
IKick, save! And...
살았다, 그런 건 안 받아요
...denied!
얘는 다시 받았어
가운데로 패스해서 올려서...
He gets it back.
Pass to the middle, lines it up....
됐다!
이렇게 멋진 패스 봤어?
Yes!
Could that shot be any prettier?
Man, you are incredible.
- 정말 대단해요
- 학교 다닐 때 해봤거든
We had a table in college.
18세기에도 이런 게 있었나요?
Really? I didn't know they had
foosball in the 1800s.
Nice mustache. At puberty,
that thing will really kick in.
콧수염이 멋지군
하지만 사춘기가 되면
얼굴이 무진장 따가울 거야
자기? 식사하세요
꼭 현모양처 같죠?
Not to sound too Florence Henderson,
but dinner's on the table.
알았어, 한 게임만 더 하고
One more point.
이런!
Score!
Now can we go?
게임 끝났는데요?
저러니 쟤랑 같이 안 하죠
That's why we don't let her play.
Is everything all right?
- 기분 괜찮아?
- 네
화내지 마, 우리가 모셨어
둘의 시간을 빼앗아서 미안해
Don't be mad at him.
It's our fault.
I'm sorry we've been hogging his time.
He's just really great
to hang out with.
정말 재미있었어
-Well....
-No, seriously.
정말이야, 얘한테도 말했지만
우리 아빠보다 훨씬 재미있어
We just talked about this.
He is so much cooler than our dads.
우리 아빠도 재미있지만
리차드는...
Our dads are okay and all,
but Richard is just
What are you kicking me for?
왜 차는 거야?
지금 얘기하는 중이잖아?
I'm trying to talk here.
그럼 여태 아빠랑 논 거야?
You guys see me as a dad?
- 그럼요
- 아니에요
-Oh, yeah!
-No!
아뇨
You're just clearly not familiar
with our young persons' vernacular.
우리들의 은어를
잘 모르시나 본데
우리가 말하는 '아빠'는
친구를 뜻해요
When we say "dad," we mean "buddy."
- 동료 말이에요
- 그렇군
We mean "pal."
정말이에요
조이도 내 아빠죠
No, seriously. Joey's my dad.
Monica's my dad.
모니카도 내 아빠고요
직장에도 아빠들이 있는걸요
I've even got some dads down at work.
That's fine.
멋지군, 모니카 아빠랑 난
분위기 좀 잡을 테니까
Well, your other dad and I are gonna
go have a romantic evening.
- 애들은 내일 놀자꾸나
- 잘 자거라
I'll just see you kids around.
Nighty-night.
- 당신은 아빠가 아니에요
- 아빠가 아니에요!
You're not a dad!
네가 다 망쳤어
I can't believe you got us
into trouble.
So are you okay?
- 괜찮아요?
- 그럼
Just...
백 살은 된 느낌이야
... I feel like I'm about a hundred.
친구가 될 수 있을 줄 알았는데
I thought I was just one of the guys.
이리 와요
내가 친구가 돼 줄게요
Come here.
I'll make you feel like
one of the guys.
진짜 멋진 사람은 그런
멍청한 게임에 흥미가 없죠
For a really cool guy,
you suck at foosball.
무슨 소리야?
내가 다 이겼다구
I was killing them.
쟤들도 멍청하니까요
Yeah, well they suck too.
곰돌이 기저귀 하나를 뜯어서
곰돌이 팬티 위에 깔아
You take the poopy diaper
and put it in the poopy diaper pail.
Calling it a "poopy diaper"
doesn't make this process any cuter.
자기한텐 곰돌이겠지만
내 눈엔 맹수로 보여
- 누구세요?
- 우리야
-It's us.
-Come on up.
이거 버리고 올게
I'll get his stuff together.
Okay, we can do this now,
can't we, Ben?
우리끼리도 할 수 있지, 벤?
할 수 있다고
그럼, 할 수 있지
Yes, we can.
There! I did it!
야, 해냈다!
I did it!
해냈어, 어디 보자
Look at that!
잘 붙어 있네
It stays on and everything.
- 안녕?
- 안녕
방금 뭐라고 했니?
혹시 '안녕' 아니었니?
I'm sorry. What did you just say?
Did you just say "hi"?
세상에, 로스!
벤이 방금 '안녕' 했어
Oh, my God! Ross?
Ben just said hi!
- 뭐?
- '안녕'이라고 했어
-What?
-Ben just said hi!
- 말을 했다고?
- 아니, 그냥 인사야
What, the word "hi"?
No, my Uncle Hi.
세상에! 그것도 놓쳤어
다 놓쳐 버렸다고
Great! And I missed that too.
I miss everything!
안됐다
내가 다시 말을 시켜볼게
Oh, I'm sorry. I guess I just
bring it out in him.
안녕, 우리예요!
-Where is he?
-We missed you.
얼마나 보고 싶었는지 몰라
이리 오렴, 벤
We missed you so much!
Come here, Ben.
Guess what?
Ben just said his first word.
벤이 방금 말을 했어요
뭐라고 했는데요?
What did he say?
Something about hi.
'안녕'이라나 어쨌다나
- 정말 대단하다
- 네가 자랑스럽구나
That's so exciting!
Mommy's so proud of you!
안녕, 안녕?
더 짧게 해야 돼요
안녕?
You know, actually,
it's more like, hi!
- 안녕?
너무 재촉하지 말죠
택시가 밑에서 기다려서...
This could go on for a while.
You're right.
We've got a cab waiting.
Well, this was fun.
한 번만 더 해보자
벤, 뭐랬다구?
We should do it again sometime, Ben.
What do you say?
- 좋아, 벤을 언제까지...
- 화요일에 올게
-All right, so I've got him...?
-Tuesday.
그래, 잘 가
Bye, you guys.
- 또 봐요
- 안녕, 벤
-Take care.
-Bye, Ben.
안녕
벤이 방금...
'안녕' 했어?
Did he just say "bye"?
He said bye!
나더러 '안녕' 한 거지?
나더러 그랬어
You said bye!
He said bye to me!
Yes, he did!
대학에 가도 되겠어요!
Suddenly I'm seeing him
go off to college!
- 가 볼게, 차가 기다려서
- 그래, 잘 가
We've gotta go.
We've got that cab downstairs.
See you later.
또 봐요
- 안녕
내가 판 구덩이 좀 봐
버트, 아주 잘 팠지?
Look at this nice deep hole I dug.
Hey, Bert...
...isn't this a nice hole here?
여긴 어니가 버트를 모래에
묻고 못 찾는 장면이란다
Ben, this is the part where Ernie buries
Bert in the sand and can't find him.
내가 미리 봤는데
나중에 다시 찾게 돼
Now, I've looked ahead on the tape,
and he does find him again.
중간에 안 좋은 장면이
있긴 하지만
But before that happens,
there's some rough going for a while.
But I think we can handle it.
우린 참을 수 있어
그 다음엔 글자가 나오는데
행복하게 끝났단 뜻일 거야
And there's just the alphabet,
but we know that ends well, so....
Here we go.
- 자, 넘어간다
- 버트, 버트?
Bert? Bert?
What happened to my friend Bert?
He was here just a moment ago.
내 친구 버트가 어디 있지?
조금 전까지도 있었는데
이런, 친구를 잃어버렸어
Oh, no! My old friend Bert is lost.
네가 있어서 다행이다
I'm so glad you're here.
Bye-bye, baby.